# Jacob Molin



+46 73 032 25 79

jacob.cb.molin@gmail.com

<u>iacobmolin.com</u>

linkedin.com/in/jacob-molin github.com/jacobmolin

#### **PROFILE**

Driven, analytical and problem-solving-loving M.Sc. student with a big interest in technology, creation and logical thinking.

With experience in music production, customer service and logistics I have a unique insight in working with and delivering results in teams with many different types of personalities. I'm curious, take initiatives and I'm always looking on how to improve products and workflows. I'm interested in exploring how technology, with the help of Al, Machine Learning and programming in general, can be used to make life better and easier for people. I thrive on new challenges and love making people laugh!

#### **EDUCATION**

Sep 2017 - (Jun 2022)

M.Sc. in Media Technology and Engineering, Linköping University - Norrköping Focus on programming and system development. Courses in Web Programming, Algorithmic Problem Solving, ML, Al and more. Expected graduation June 2022.

Bachelor project: In an agile team of seven where we researched implementation methods and developed an online price comparison service which collects data by web scraping online stores. We worked according to Scrum and my focus laid on collecting, comparing and organizing data by writing Python scripts.

Mar 2013 - Jun 2014

Independent Music Production Certificate, UCLA Extension, Westwood CA - USA

Sep 2010 - Sep 2011

Audio Engineering Cert. (Music and Post-Prod.), Musicians Institute, Hollywood CA - USA

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Jun 2021 -

Software Developer, Gaia, Norrköping

Summer internship and part time during studies. The internship was based on two use cases involving automatic re-routing of bus traffic and speech-to-text tools control for bus drivers. I learned techniques like Docker, Azure, Angular, Valhalla Routing and OpenStreetMap as well as working in an agile team. During the fall I've continued working with automatic position data generation in Python and C#.

Aug 2019 - Jun 2020

Programming tutor at LiTHeHack, Linköping University, Norrköping

Employed by LiU to tutor for two sessions per week. I learned how to quickly understand the issue the student had, come up with a possible solution and guiding the student in finding a solution by themselves. Most questions regarded C++, JavaScript and MATLAB.

Aug 2016 - Jul 2018

Location / Production Assistant on film sets, Freelance, Stockholm

Setting up and maintaining film location sets for projects like "Solsidan" and "Hassel". Developed skills in managing multiple issues at once and running my own company.

Aug 2014 - Aug 2017

Audio Engineer / Music Producer, Freelance, Los Angeles / Stockholm

Audio engineer for artists like Zara Larsson, Dua Lipa, Rev Run and Jared Leto. Music producer for artists like Broderick Batts, Taps and Diana Ebe. I learned how to work in and lead teams of very different minded people towards a common goal.

Apr 2012 - Nov 2012

**Sound / Light Technician, Sports Entertainer**, Hotels Viva, Mallorca - Spain

By leading sports activities for hotel guests during the day and running sound / light for stage shows at night I developed my skills in providing great customer service.

### **COMMISSIONS OF TRUST**

Mav 2020 - Mav 2021	Auditor, NAFF	I (Norrköping's Acac	demic Sports Association	on). Norrköping

As one of two auditors, being responsible for auditing the accounting and financial

situation of NAFFI for the academic year 2019/2020.

May 2018 – May 2019 Chairman, NAFFI (Norrköping's Academic Sports Association), Norrköping

I was responsible for running board meetings and ultimately responsible for the weekly and overall operations. I learned how to be responsible for a team and making sure all

work was on track.

### PROJECTS IN AND OUT OF SCHOOL

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021	Battleship AI Agent —	Project in the course "Al 1	for Interactive Media".	. Linköping University

Together with two fellow students we're now developing an AI agent to solve the game Battleship using a Convolutional Neural Network. We're using *Python* and *TensorFlow* to implement the agent. Go to <a href="mailto:github.com/jacobmolin/battleship\_ai\_agent">github.com/jacobmolin/battleship\_ai\_agent</a> to see the

GitHub repo.

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 EnRoute – Project in the course "Advanced Web Programming", Linköping University

Together with two fellow students we built an online version of the board game "Ticket to Ride". We used techniques like *Node.js*, *React*, *Socket.io*. See the GitHub repo with link to

demo at github.com/angelgravel/enroute.

Oct 2020 – Nov 2020 Resume and portfolio website: jacobmolin.com, Own initiative

Developed my own resume and portfolio website to learn more about web development!

Implemented with *React* and *Next.js*.

Sep 2019 – Nov 2019 VizWiz - Project in the course "Audio Physics", Linköping University

Developed, in a group of three, an online frequency spectrum analyzer with JavaScript

and *React*. Go to <u>jacobmolin.com/portfolio</u> for link to demo and GitHub repo.

Oct 2018 – Jan 2019 diatot - Project in the course "Communication and User Interface (UI)", Linköping University

With focus on the UI, the group of four developed a mobile phone adapted website for diabetics to calculate a meal dose of insulin. The goal was to simplify the everyday life of diabetics by letting them spend less time managing their disease. Implemented using JavaScript and React. Go to <a href="mailto:iocom/portfolio">iocom/portfolio</a> for link to demo and GitHub repo.

#### **SKILLS**

Language			Programming							
	Swedish (Native)	••••	C++	••••	Next.js	••••	Angular	••••	Git	••••
	English	••••	Python	••••	React	••••	HTML/CSS	••••	SQL	••••
			Java	••••	Docker	••••	JavaScript	••••	C#	••••

## **PERSONAL**

I'm originally from Stockholm, but now I live and study in Norrköping. I spent four years in Los Angeles studying and working in music recording and production, where I had the opportunity to work with major artists, producers and songwriters. In the end I decided that I wanted to pursue a career within programming and technology development, which has been a big interest for me since I was a kid. My biggest passion of all is to learn new things, not only within technology and programming, but also about things like other cultures or how to run a business. In my spare time I love playing music, exercising, travelling, experiencing nature, listen to podcasts and having a great time with my friends.

I hope we'll have the chance to meet soon!